So as we know S3 Buckets
are linked to only one region
and so sometimes you are looking
to transfer files from all around the world
into one specific S3 buckets.
And there is a way to speed up the transfer
using S3 transfer acceleration.
The way it works is that
your file is for example
being uploaded from the United States
into this war bucket in Australia.
And so what we'll do is that
we'll upload the file into a edge location
that is going to be very close to a user in the USA
and then using the internal network.
The education will transfer the file
to the S3 Buckets in Australia
in a more reliable and fast connection.
So this is the basics of how S3 transfer acceleration works.
And this is only used when you want to upload
or download a file from this bucket.
That is far away from you.
The cool thing is that
we can test the tool and see how effective it is for us.
Using this URL so let's have a go.
So I am on the URL address.
I had in the slide
and as we can see it is going to run some tests
of the speed connection.
If I did a direct upload into an Amazon S3 bucket
in U.S. east one
or if I use an S3 accelerated transfer upload
and so we'll see the difference
and how much performance gain we gain
if we are uploading the data
in two different S3 buckets around the world.
And so to give you an idea
I am recording this from Europe
and so Northern Virginia is a bit far away from me
and so I expect the transfer acceleration
to be a bit faster.
But again my internet is really good
so it really depends on where you are located
and the type of Internet you have
to see if transfer acceleration
is worth it for you or not.
So as we can see for Virginia
using a S3 transfer acceleration
is about 13 percent faster
and this will also do the test in all the other regions.
So we have San Francisco, Oregon, Dublin, Frankfurt,
Tokyo, Seoul, Mumbai, Ohio, Canada and so on.
So I wait for the test to be over
and get back to you with the results
so if we look at the results
of these S3 transfer acceleration
I can see that I am faster in San Francisco,
Oregon, Dublin I'm actually faster pretty much everywhere.
So this is for us a way to tell us that
S3 transfer acceleration
is a really really good way
to speed up the downloads into Amazon history
and the upload as well.
And so it would be something you would be using
if you had a global application
that needs to upload files
into a specific Amazon S3 bucket.
So hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.